Story: An Unusual Tuesday
قِصَّة: يَوْم تَلَات مِشْ عَادِي
It was Tuesday,
"كَانْ يَوْمِ التَّلَات،
and I went to a wedding.
وَأَنَا رُحْتِ فَرَح.
There was a groom and a bride,
كَانْ فِيهِ الْعَرِيس وِالْعَرُوسَه،
and many guests.
وِضُيُوف كِتِير.
But the groom and the bride were arguing.
بَسِّ الْعَرِيس وِالْعَرُوسَه كَانُوا مِتْخَانْقِين.
The guests were surprised.
الضُّيُوف كَانُوا مِسْتَغْرَبِين.
When the party was over,
لَمَّا الْفَرَحْ خِلِص،
we went to watch a play.
رُحْنَا نِتْفَرَّجْ عَلَى مَسْرَحِيَّه.
In the play, there was a magician.
فِي الْمَسْرَحِيَّه كَانْ فِيهْ سَاحِر.
The magician said,
السَّاحِرْ قَال:
"I won't be a puppet in your hands."
"مِشْ هَبْقَى لِعْبَه فِي إِيدَك!"
All the people laughed.
كُلِّ النَّاسْ ضِحْكِت.
After that, I saw a pilot
بَعْدِ كِدَه شُفْتِ طَيَّارْ
sitting with his friends.
قَاعِدْ مَعَ أَصْحَابُه.
Talk to us a little bit
اتْكَلَّمْنَا شْوَيَّه
about corruption in the state.
عَنِ الْفَسَادْ فِي الدَّوْلَه.
I was speaking slowly,
أَنَا كُنْتِ بَتْكَلَّمْ بَطِيء
meaning I was speaking at a relaxed pace.
يَعْنِي كُنْتِ بَتْكَلَّمْ بِرَاحَه،
But after a while,
لَكِنْ بَعْدِ شْوَيَّه
I was able to speak quickly.
أَنَا كُنْتِ قَادِرْ أَتْكَلَّمْ بِسُرْعَه.
After that, we went to look at
بَعْدِ كِدَه رُحْنَا نِتْفَرَّجْ
the Hindu temple.
عَلَى مَعْبَدْ هِنْدِي،
And we went home on Thursday.
وِرِجِعْنَا الْبَيْت يَوْمِ الْخَمِيس.
And that was the end of the week.
وِكَانْ دَهْ آخِرِ الْأُسْبُوع